Encounters are mysterious! But cases are even more so!
لقاءات البشر مغلّفة بالغموض، والقضايا تلفّها طبقات أكثر حتّى
I'm so glad to have met you!
!أنا مسرورٌ حقّاً لكوني معك
Today's earthenware is second to none!
!أواني اليوم الخزفية لا نظير لها
And the mystery is on the national treasure level!
!والقضيّة ولغزها على مستوى كنز وطنيّ
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
Eh?! You got a call from Kikuemon?!
ماذا؟ تلقّيت اتّصالاً من كيكويمون؟
Yep! From the very man himself!
!أجل، من الرجل بنفسه
Who's Kikuemon again?
من كان كيكويمون مُجدداً؟
You've never heard of Kikuemon, the living national treasure?
لم تسمعي بالكنز الوطنيّ الحيّ، كيكويمون؟
He's a potter, Ran-neechan.
إنّه فخّاري يا ران-نيتشان
Geez...
...يا إلهي
So, what did someone so great want with you, Dad?
ما الذي يريده شخص رفيع المقام مثله منك يا أبي؟
He said he'd give details when we meet.
قال أنّه سيخبرني بالتفاصيل عند لقائنا
He wants me to visit him in West Tama this Sunday with my family.
يريد منّي زيارته في تاما الغربيّة يوم الأحد القادم مع عائلتي
With your family? I guess it's not about hiring you, then.
مع عائلتك؟ ربما ليس طلب تحرٍّ إذاً
No, there's no telling.
لا جزم بذلك
Being with the family might be a type of camouflage.
فكونك رفقة العائلة قد يكون تمويهاً
Camouflage?
تمويه؟
To keep others from realizing I'm investigating a case.
لإخفاء كون الأمر طلب تحرٍّ عن الآخرين
He probably wanted to come here himself, but he is almost 80!
أراد القدوم هنا بنفسه غالباً، لكنّه شيخٌ اقترب من الثمانين
Oh! You're so good at reading into things, Dad!
هكذا إذاً، أنت تجيد قراءة الأمور !حقّاً يا أبي
Of course I am!
!بالطبع
If Kikuemon-san is a living national treasure of pottery,
إذا كان كيكويمون-سان كنزاً ،وطنياً حيّاً في الفِخارة
I'm a living national treasure of detectiving!
!فأنا كنزٌ وطنيّ حيّ في التحرّي
Yeah, that optimistic personality is on the national treasure level...
بالفعل، شخصيتك المتفائلة هذه على مستوى كنزٍ وطنيّ
Wow! This color, this shape... it's a true masterpiece!
مذهل! اللون والشكل يوحيان !بأنّه تحفة بحقّ
Just as I'd expect from the work of a living national treasure!
كما يُتوقع من أعمال الكنز !الوطنيّ الحيّ، كيكويمون-سان
Please don't call me a national treasure.
لا تنادني بالكنز الوطنيّ رجاءً
I'm a person, not a thing.
أنا شخص، ولستُ غرضاً
Kikuemon (78) (Tsuchiya Mankichi) Ceramic Artist
(كيكويمون (78 تسوتشيا مانكيتشي) فنّان خزفي)
Here you are!
تفضّلي
Thank you!
شكراً
Oh, this isn't much, but...
...بالمناسبة، هذا ليس كثيراً، لكن
Oh, sponge cake! Wonderful! I just love it! Thank you!
،كاستيلا! يسعدني ذلك !فأنا أحبّها كثيراً! شكراً لك
So, what did you need to see me for?
إذاً، لمَ استدعيتني؟
Do you need me to see if your young wife is having an affair?
أتحتاج منّي التحرّي في خيانة زوجتك الشابة؟
No, no. She's my son's wife.
كلا، إنّها زوجة ابني
She's been taking care of things for me for a while.
كانت تعتني بأموري المعيشية لفترة
Sadly, my wife and son both died in a car accident two years ago.
لقت زوجتي وابني حتفهما لسوء الحظّ في حادث مروري قبل عامين
I'm sorry to hear it...
...يؤسفني سماع ذلك
I've asked you here for but one reason:
استدعيتُك اليوم لسببٍ واحد
to ask the opinion of the great detective everyone is talking about!
!وهو أخذ رأي المتحرّي العظيم ذائع الصيت
I've noticed your deductions as of late have been so full of flaws!
!لاحظتُ أنّ استنتاجاتك مؤخراً مليئة بالفجوات
F-Flaws?
فـ-فجوات؟
That's right! For example, the case last month--
...صحيح! على سبيل المثال، قضيّة الشهر الفائت
Now, now! Don't act haughty, Father!
مهلك، لا تتصرّف بتعالٍ يا أبتاه
Just be honest and say you're a big fan
كُن صريحاً وأخبره أنّك معجبٌ كبير
Tsuchiya Masuko (42) Kikuemon's son's wife
(تسوتشيا ماسوكو (42 زوجة ابن كيكويمون
of the great Mori Kogoro-san!
!بالمتحرّي العظيم موري كوغورو-سان
M-Masuko-san!
!ماسوكو-سان
He's a big fan?!
معجب كبير؟
Yes!
أجل
He gets so excited whenever Mori-san solves a case!
يتحمّس كثيراً كلّما يحلّ موري-سان قضيّة
In fact, he just put up a big fuss
في الواقع، أثار جلبةً كبيرة
when I forgot to file an article from the other day about a case of his!
عندما نسيتُ أرشفة مقالة في ذاك !اليوم عن إحدى قضاياه
C-Come, now!
!مـ-مهلك
Okay, yeah, it's true!
!حسناً، ذلك صحيح
Oh, he's here!
!أتى
Wow! It's really him!
!مُذهل! إنّه هو نفسه
Who're those two?
من هذين؟
My pupils. Let me introduce you.
تلميذاي، سأقدّمهما لك
This is Arita-kun.
،هذا آريتا-كن
Arita Yoshihiko (36) Kikuemon's pupil
(آريتا يوشيهيكو (36 تلميذ كيكويمون
His skill has made leaps and bounds, and his work shows promise.
،ارتفعت مهاراته لحدٍّ كبير وتظهر أعماله قدرة واعدة
Hi!
مرحباً
On the other hand is Seto-kun.
بينما سيتو-كن في الجانب الآخر
Seto Ryuichi (35) Kikuemon's pupil
(سيتو ريويتشي (35 تلميذ كيكويمون
His works have dropped in number, and he's stuck in a standstill.
الذي تناقصت أعماله، وهو أمام حائطٍ الآن
I'm just in a slump, that's all!
أعاني هبوطاً مؤقتاً لا أكثر
That's what you get for always copying our master!
!ذلك ما تناله لتقليد المعلّم دوماً
Aw, shut up!
!اخرس
Please, pull yourself together, Seto-san!
!اضبط نفسك أكثر يا سيتو-سان
You're to be the sixth-generation Kikuemon, after all!
فأنت من سيكون كيكويمون الجيل السادس
Sixth-generation?
الجيل السادس؟
The Kikuemon name has been passed down from master to pupil.
نُقل مُسمى كيكويمون عبر الأجيال من المعلّم لتلميذه
I'm the fifth.
أنا الخامس
Anyway, tell us what kind of pottery Detective Mori chose!
بصرف النظر عن ذلك، أخبرنا أيّ آنية فخّارية !اختارها المتحرّي موري
Yeah!
!أجل
Hold your horses! I still haven't told him!
مهلكما، لم أخبره بعد
What are they talking about?
ما الذي يقصدانه؟
I want you to have one of my works.
أريدك أن تتلقّى أحد أعمالي
I could've brought one to your office,
،كان بإمكاني جلبه لمكتبك
but I wanted you to choose one for yourself.
لكنّي أردت منك الاختيار بنفسك
Well, make your choice. Any of the ones in this room.
هيّا، فلتختر أيّ ما تشاء بين أواني هذه الغرفة
Y-You're sure?
أ-أيمكنني حقّاً؟
They're all masterpieces, worth millions of yen each!
كلّها قطع فنّية يصل ثمنها لعدّة ملايين ينّات
M-Millions?
مـ-ملايين؟
Hold on, Dad. This is too generous. Show some restraint, okay?
!انتظر يا أبي، هذا كثير فلتظهر بعض التحفّظ
Yeah, I know.
أعرف ذلك
In that case...
...في تلك الحالة
I guess I'll just choose this cup!
!لعلّي سأختار هذا الكأس
Just as I'd expect from a great detective! You have sharp eyes!
كما أتوقّع من المتحرّي العظيم، نظراتك حادّة
Looks like I win the bet!
يبدو أنّي فزت بالرهان
Bet?
رهان؟
We all bet on what you would choose.
راهنّا جميعاً على ما ستختاره بين أواني البيت
And, just as I expected you would, you chose that cup,
وكما توقّعت، اخترت هذا الكأس
which is hailed the world over as a masterware!
والمُصنّف عالمياً من أرقى القطع
It was just dumb luck...
...كانت محض مصادفة
Masterware indeed...
قطعة راقية إذاً؟
I never intended to give that away, but I don't mind in your case!
لم أنو إعطاءه لأحد، لكن لا أمانع في حالتك
But, Father!
!لكن يا أبتاه
Oh, yes. I'd also like Mori-san to see the Fusui-maru, my latest work.
أجل، أودّ أن يطّلع موري-سان أيضاً على آخر أعمالي الذي سأعلن عنه، فوسوي مارو
Could you bring it from the storeroom?
هلّا جلبتِه من المستودع؟
Y-Yes. Right away.
أ-أجل، فوراً
Oh, come to think of it, I don't see Otani-kun...
...بالمناسبة، لا أرى أوتاني-كن
Yes, he's by the kiln.
أجل، إنّه عند القمين
Perfect!
ممتاز
Mori-san! Won't you come see the kiln?
موري-سان، هلّا رافقتني لرؤية القمين؟
Oh, sure.
حسناً
Umm, about how much is that cup worth?
المعذرة، ما مقدار قيمة هذا الكأس؟
Hmm. If it had a price, it'd maybe go for about 10 million yen?
حسناً، إذا كنتُ سأعطيه ثمناً فسيكون قرابة 10 ملايين ينّ
10 million?!
!عـ-عشرة ملايين؟
You're such a joker! You already knew that!
!يا لعبثك، كنت تعرف ذلك سلفاً
I shouldn't have made that bet...
كان عليّ ألا أدخل ذاك الرهان
It's worth 10 million...
...قيمته 10 ملايين
T-That's a thousand 10,000 yen bills...
!أ-أي ألف ورقة 10 آلاف ينّ
What a big kiln!
يا للقمين الكبير
How is it going, Otani-kun?
أوتاني-كن، كيف يمضي الأمر؟
Oh, I should be able to fire it before dinner.
حسناً، أتوقّع أنّي سأستطيع إتمام الإشعال قبل العشاء
Otani Kaoru (36) Kikuemon's Pupil
(أوتاني كاورو (36 تلميذ كيكويمون
Say, what is this pile of broken pieces?
أخبرني، ما كومة القطع المكسورة هذه؟
The remains of pottery that the lady of the house demolished.
بقايا الأواني الفخّارية التي حطّمتها سيّدة المنزل
D-Demolished? By that woman?
حـ-حطّمتها؟ تلك المرأة؟
Yes. Despite how she seems, she has a very sharp eye.
أجل، تملك نظراً حاداً بخلاف ما يبدو عليها
So, our master won't look at anything that doesn't meet her standards.
لذا لا يطّلع معلّمنا على شيء لم يطابق معاييرها
After all, she has the eyes that my son, who was to be my successor,
إنّها تحمل عيني المرأة التي وقع ابني في حبّها
fell in love with.
وكان يُفترض أن يكون خليفتي
That's why I've left her in charge of deciding
لذا تركتُ لها مسؤولية تحديد
who will succeed the Kikuemon name after I die.
من سيرث اسم كيكويمون بعد مماتي
But hasn't she been a bit strict lately?
لكن أليست صارمةً كثيراً مؤخراً؟
You have it good! She only okayed two of my wares this month!
أنت أحسن منّي حالاً، لم تقبل منّي إلّا قطعتين من فخّارياتي هذا الشهر
She hasn't okayed one of mine in three months...
لم تقبل أيّاً من فخّارياتي ...للثلاثة أشهر الفائتة
I guess I'm at my limit now...
لعلّ إبداعي قد توقّف
Any uncertainty in the heart soon shows up in earthenware.
التردد في القلب ينعكس على الفخّاريات فوراً
Any pottery made with such feelings will also be bent out of shape.
أيّ فخّار مشكّل بتلك المشاعر سيختلّ شكله أيضاً
Calm your mind like the water of a still lake, and it will naturally--
،اجعل ذهنك ساكناً مثل ماء البحيرة ...وستستطيع طبيعياً تشكيل
Hey! Was that her just now?!
!أليس ذلك صوت السيّدة؟
It came from the storeroom...
أتى من المستودع؟
I-It couldn't be!
!أ-أيمكن؟
The Fusui-maru!
!فوسوي مارو
I can't believe this!
!يا للهول
I-I'm so sorry! It tumbled down when I went to climb the ladder!
!أ-أنا آسفة! سقط عندما هممتُ بصعود السلّم
U-Uhh, really, I didn't mean to...
...أ-أنا، صدقاً
No matter. All that has shape will someday break.
لا يهمّ، كلّ ما يتجسّد مصيره التفكّك
The Fusui-maru has simply returned to the earth.
رجع فوسوي مارو للأرض فحسب
You students can take care of this.
سأدع تلامذتي يتكفلون بالأمر
Masuko-san, you can start on the nice meal for Mori-san.
بينما ماسوكو-سان، يمكنك البدء بتحضير الوجبة الفاخرة لموري-سان
R-Right.
حـ-حسناً
I'm a tad exhausted. Please don't wake me until dinner.
أشعر ببعض الإرهاق، لا توقظوني حتّى العشاء رجاءً
This must be Otani's "everything gets broken" curse!
لا بدّ أنّها لعنة "كلّ شيء ينكسر" الخاصّة بأوتاني
No, it's not!
!كلا
Umm, do you need any help?
المعذرة، أتحتاج لمساعدة؟
Oh, we'll clean up here. You can relax in the living room.
لا، سنتولّى نحن التنظيف هنا فيمكنكم الاسترخاء في غرفة المعيشة
I-I see.
هـ-هكذا إذاً
What's this?
ما هذا؟
A marble?
كرة رخامية؟
I haven't had enough to drink! Keep it coming!
!لم أشرب ما يكفي! هاتوا المزيد
Is she a bad drunk?
أهي ممن يعانون في الثمل؟
Yes, her personality changes whenever she drinks!
أجل، تتغيّر شخصيّتها عندما تشرب
But, is it really okay to accept something so valuable?
لكن أيمكننا قبول شيء قيّم لذاك الحدّ حقّاً؟
You don't need to act reserved!
!لا داعي للتحفّظ
He isn't long for this world, anyway! He can't make much anymore!
لم يتبق لأبتاه وقت كثير في هذا العالم !بأيّ حال، لا يمكنه صنع المزيد
Isn't that right, Father?
أليس كذلك؟
M-Madam!
!سيّدتي
Now, now.
لا داعي
It's true, I'm up there in age.
صحيحٌ أنّي طاعن في السنّ
I can only make two or three decent things a year now.
لا يمكنني سوى صنع قطعتين أو ثلاث لائقة في العام
Huh? I seem to recall you exhibited ten or so items last year...
ماذا؟ أذكر أنّك عرضت عشر قطع ...أو ما يقاربها العام الفائت
Never mind pottery! Let's hear about some more of your cases!
!يكفي من الفخّاريات! احك لنا المزيد عن قضاياك
Yes, good idea!
!فكرة حسنة
Then tell us about the Tsukikage Island case!
!أخبرنا عن قضيّة جزيرة تسوكيكاغي إذاً
I wanna hear about the Kiri Tengu!
!أريد السماع عن تينغو الضباب
Then how about the incident that happened during my class reunion?
ما رأيكما بالحادثة التي وقعت أثناء مناسبة لمّ شمل فصلي إذاً؟
You just told us that one!
حكيتها لنا قبل قليل
And the art museum one and magician one!
كذلك قضيّة متحف الفنون، وقضيّة الساحر
Let's see... That leaves...
...حسناً... ذلك يترك
Those were the only three that you actually solved while conscious...
كانت تلك القضايا الثلاث الوحيدة ...التي حلّها وهو واعٍ
Umm, you'll catch cold if you sleep here...
المعذرة، سيصيبك الزكام إذا نمتِ هنا
It's no use. She's not easily woken once she falls asleep drunk.
لا جدوى، لا تستيقظ بسهولة بعدما تنام من الثمالة
Oh well. I guess I'll carry her to her room.
ليس باليد حيلة، سأحملها لغرفتها
Hey! Hurry back!
!ارجع بسرعة
Yeah, I know!
!أعرف
After that, the party continued late into the night.
بعد ذلك، استمرّت الحفلة لوقتٍ متأخّر
The seven people in the stateroom forgot all their worries,
،ونسي السبعة في غرفة المعيشة كلّ همومهم
drank up, and made merry.
وغرقوا في الشراب وأثاروا جلبةً كبيرة
Little did we know that a horrible incident we'd never forget
كنّا جاهلين عن وقوع حادثةً فظيعة
would be waiting for us in a few hours' time...
...لن ننساها أبداً بعد بضعة ساعات
What? It's already 8:00!
!ماذا؟ أصبحت الثامنة بالفعل
I hate to ask, but could you go wake Masuko-san?
المعذرة، لكن هلّا أيقظت ماسوكو-سان؟
I'd like to have some rice and tea.
أودّ تناول أرزٍّ وشاي
Yes.
حاضر
You slept here too, Ran-neechan?
نمتِ هنا أيضاً يا ران-نيتشان؟
Something wrong with that?
أهناك خطبٌ في ذلك؟
Mori-san! It's morning! Mori-san!
!موري-سان! حلّ الصباح! موري-سان
He's deep asleep...
...إنّه نائمٌ بعمق
It's only natural, Master.
لا عجب يا معلّم
After all, he is "Sleeping Kogoro"!
!فهو معروفٌ بأنّه كوغورو النائم
Yes, that's a good point!
!أجل، معك حقّ
Umm, her futon is empty...
المعذرة، فراشها فارغ
That's odd. Where could she have gone this early in the morning?
غريب، أين ذهبت في هذا الوقت الباكر؟
Maybe she went to buy some things for breakfast?
ربما نفدت مكوّنات الإفطار وذهبت لشرائها
Should we give her a call? She did have a cell phone with her...
هل نتّصل بها؟ فهي تحمل هاتفاً خلوياً معها
Yes, please do.
أجل، افعلوا ذلك
I can't have anything too heavy first thing in the morning.
لا أريد تناول طعامٍ ثقيل في الصباح الباكر
That's strange. She's not answering.
غريب، إنّها لا تجيب
W-What was that?!
!ما-ما كان ذاك الصوت؟
It sounded like pottery breaking!
!بـ-بدا أنّه صوت تحطّم فخّار
Hey, now! Don't tell me someone's inside the storeroom?!
أيمكن أنّ هناك أحداً في المستودع؟
K-Kid!
!يا-يا فتى
M-Madam!
!سـ-سيّدتي
She hanged herself just now! She might survive if we get her down!
!يُفترض أنّها شنقت نفسها للتوّ فقط !قد نستطيع إنقاذها إذا أنزلناها فوراً
Hurry!
!أسرعوا
I'll get her legs! Otani, hold her steady!
!سأحمل ساقيها! ثبّت أنت جسدها يا أوتاني
Right!
!حسناً
I'll undo the rope!
!سأفكّ الحبل
Hurry!
!أسرع
Lay her down here!
!لننزلها هنا
We're too late! She's dead!
فات الأوان، فارقت الحياة
Master. Contact the police.
معلّم، لنتّصل بالشرطة
Yes.
أجل
That's strange! Those are missing, yet...
...غريب، ذلك غير موجود، فلمَ
Could this mean...
...أيمكنّ أنّ هذا
The deceased is Tsuchiya Masuko, age 42.
المُتوفاة هي تسوتشيا ماسوكو-سان، 42 عاماً
The wife of the son of Kikuemon-san, the head of this house...
زوجة ابن كيكويمون-سان، سيّد هذا المنزل
And you were all in the stateroom when you heard something break?
،وكنتم في غرفة المعيشة القريبة من المستودع
Y-Yes. We had partied late into the night yesterday.
أ-أجل، فقد احتفلنا هناك البارحة حتّى وقتٍ متأخّر
She went to sleep first, so I carried her to her room.
نامت السيّدة أوّلاً، فنقلتُها لغرفتها
Her futon was empty when I went to wake her this morning.
لكن كان فراشها فارغاً عندما ذهبتُ لإيقاظها هذا الصباح
Just before we went to look for her, we heard something break,
قبل ذهابنا للبحث عنها، سمعنا صوت تحطّم شيء
and when we rushed here, we found her...
...وعندما هرعنا إلى هنا، وجدناها قد
The sound was of the pottery that's lying in pieces on the floor.
كان ذلك صوت القطعة الفخّارية متناثرة الأجزاء على الأرض
She had probably stood on it when hanging herself.
وقفت عليها قبل شنق نفسها غالباً
It's been trampled on quite a bit...
فقد دُهست لحدٍّ كبير
S-Sorry, Inspector. We stepped on it.
ا-المعذرة حضرة المفتّش، فكنّا نحن من دهسناها
That little boy said she might live if we brought her down quickly...
قال ذاك الفتى أنّها قد تنجو إذا أنزلناها فوراً
H-Hold on!
!أ-أنت
What do you think you're doing?
ما الذي تفعله؟
And, soundly asleep as always despite just happening to be present...
،ومن صادف وجوده هنا هذه المرّة ...وكان نائماً أثناء وقوع الحادثة
...is you again, Mori-kun?!
!أنت مجدداً يا موري-كن؟
P-Please don't shout. I have a hangover and my head is killing me...
!لا-لا تصرخ رجاءً حضرة المفتّش ...أعاني آثار الثمل ورأسي يوجعني
This isn't funny!
!لا تعبث معي
Every place you go, there's a pile of dead bodies! Do you get it?!
!كلّ مكان تذهب له تتراكم فيه الجثث! أتفهم؟
I-I'm sorry?
...آ-آسف
Inspector. There are no signs that anyone climbed onto the beams.
حضرة المفتّش، لا آثار لصعود أحدٍ على العارضة
That so?
هكذا إذاً
That ladder doesn't reach to the roof beams, either;
لا يصل ذاك السلّم عارضة السقف أيضاً
something must've been tied to the end of the rope and thrown over.
لا بدّ أنّ شيئاً ما رُبط بطرف الحبل، ثم رُمي فوقها
And there seem to be plenty of things to tie to it here...
ويبدو أنّ هناك الكثير من الأشياء التي يمكنك ربطها به أيضاً
But would anyone use such important works of art?
لكن هل تستعمل قطعاً فنّية ثمينة لذلك؟
The shelves don't hold just the master's work, but ours as well.
لا تحوي الرفوف أعمال معلّمنا فقط، بل أعمالنا أيضاً
If she had used anything, it probably would've been ours.
إذا استعملت السيّدة شيّئاً، فلا بد أنّها إحدى قطعنا
Still, these certainly are immaculate...
لكنّ هذه لامعة النظافة حقّاً
We did spring cleaning not too long ago...
قمنا بتنظيف الربيع قبل فترة قصيرة
Which means the last remaining issue...
...ما يعني أنّ المشكلة الأخيرة المتبقّية
...is this open cut on her calf.
هو الجرح المفتوح في ربلة ساقها
There seems to have been quite a lot of blood, too.
ويحيط بها الكثير من الدم أيضاً
She probably messed up and fell to the floor the first time.
لا بدّ أنّها فشلت وسقطت على الأرض في المرّة الأولى
When she did, she cut her leg on a piece of the pot
أثناء ذلك، أُصيبت رجلها بإحدى قطع الإناء الأوّل
but ignored it and tried again.
لكنّها تجاهلت ذلك وأعادت الكرّة
It's not uncommon for a noose to be so big that the head slips out,
من الشائع أنّ تكون الأنشوطة كبيرةً بحيث يخرج الرأس
or for a weak knot to come undone.
أو تكون الربطة ضعيفة فتنحلّ
There's blood everywhere because she probably writhed around.
الدمّ منتشر لأنّها كانت تترنّح غالباً
But I'm pretty sure we only heard one pot break...
لكنّي سمعت صوت تحطّم إناء مرّة واحدة وفقما أذكر
Then her first attempt must've been while you were still asleep.
كانت محاولتها الفاشلة بينما كنتم لا تزالون نائمين إذاً
If the rope had come untied, it would've taken too long to fix it.
إذا انحلّت عقدة الحبل، فستحتاج وقتاً لإصلاحها
But why would she commit suicide?
لكن لمَ أقدمت على الانتحار؟
She didn't seem like the type at all...
لم يبد عليها أنّها من ذاك الصنف أبداً
Can you think of any reasons?
ألديكم فكرة عن الدافع؟
She was drinking so happily just last night...
...كانت تشرب ببهجةٍ البارحة
The Fusui-maru.
فوسوي مارو
She most likely did this out of regret for breaking the Fusui-maru.
لا بدّ أنّها أٌقدمت على هذا من ندمها بعد تحطيمها لفوسوي مارو
The poor woman...
يا للمسكينة
Fusui-maru?
فوسوي مارو؟
The master's latest pot, which was to be put on exhibition soon.
آخر إناء للمعلّم الذي كان سيعلن عنه في معرض قريباً
She broke it yesterday when she came to get it from the storeroom.
حطّمته بالأمس عندما ذهبت لجلبه في الظهيرة من المستودع
If she had been deeply troubled by it, then...
...لو كان ذلك يضايقها بعمق، فربما
Then, it's not out of the question?
أي أنّه ليس مستبعداً؟
Yes, she had the motive and circumstances for this to be a suicide.
بالفعل، يوجد الدافع والظروف الضروريّة بحيث يبدو هذا انتحاراً
But...
...لكن
Examiner.
أيّها المُحلّل
Please compare the cut with the shapes of the broken pieces.
قارن الجرح على الجثّة مع أشكال القطع المكسورة من فضلك
Yes, sir.
حاضر
But the pieces have been trampled quite a lot,
لكنّ القطع قد دُهست كثيراً فطرأت عليها تغييرات
so I can't say if any will match the cut...
...لذا لا أعرف إن كانت ستطابق الجرح
A match would make this question go away, but...
...أيّ مطابقة كانت لتمحو هذا السؤال، لكن
Suicide! It's clearly a suicide!
!انتحار! انتحار! من الواضح أنّه كان انتحاراً
Hey, now!
...أنت
Ouch!
!مؤلم
What's wrong, Conan-kun?!
!ما الخطب يا كونان-كن؟
I stepped on a broken piece...
...وطأتُ على القطع المكسورة
What's with you? You aren't wearing anything on your feet...
ما خطبك؟ لا تنتعل شيئاً
I can't help it! I rushed here! That lady's the same way!
!أتيتُ هنا بعجلة! الأمر ينطبق على تلك السيّدة
Come to think of it, I don't see her footwear anywhere...
...بذكرك ذلك، لا أرى أيّ حذاءٍ لها
But it's strange.
لكن هذا غريب
If she came barefoot, the bottoms of her feet should be dirty like mine.
إذا أتيت حافية القدمين، فيُفترض أن يكون أخمصا قدميها متّسخين مثلي
Now that you mention it, the bottoms of her feet aren't dirty!
!صـ-صحيح، أخمصا قدميها ليسا متّسخين
Oh! Then maybe someone carried her here?
فهمت! ربما حملها أحدهم إلى هنا؟
Y-You're not saying--
...أ-أتقصد
She was murdered, then?!
!أي أنّها قُتلت؟
If so, then that places the suspicion on all of you,
في تلك الحالة، سيتوجّه اللوم نحوكم
Could it be?!
!أيمكن؟
Yes! This is it!
!وجدتها! هذه هي
I finally found a trace that the killer failed to hide!
وجدت الأثر الذي فشل القاتل !في إخفائه أخيراً
Using this method, you wouldn't need to be in the room to kill her!
باستعمال هذه الطريقة، يمكن ارتكاب الجريمة !دون الحاجة للتواجد في الغرفة حتّى
Just what did you find?
ما الذي وجدته بالضبط؟
Evidence that the killer failed to hide completely!
!دليل فشلَ القاتل في إخفائه تماماً
On the next Conan...
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
The Famous Potter Murder Case (Part 2).
جريمة قتل الفخّاري الشهير (الجزء الثاني)
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Lipstick.
أحمر شفاه
Next episode features a hidden pitfall.
في الحلقة القادمة حفرة سقوط !في موضع لا تراه
You can't know it's there if you can't see it.
لا يمكن أن تعرف إذا لم ترَ